{
    "id": "8f4dfa616f0f42bfb97b1295d8d53d8e",
    "title": "Gerund Or Infinitive",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She advised him …………………………. medicine.",
            "description": "Advise is followed by object + to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "study",
                "to study",
                "studying"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They warned us …………………………….. late.",
            "description": "The negative form of the infinitive is made by putting not before to.",
            "answers": [
                "to not be",
                "not to be",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Who taught you ……………………………..?",
            "description": "Teach is followed by object + to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "swim",
                "to swim",
                "swimming"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You must not miss ……………………………… him.",
            "description": "Miss is followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to see",
                "see",
                "seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I cannot permit you ……………………………..",
            "description": "Permit is followed by object + to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "going",
                "to go"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I suggest …………………………….. a doctor.",
            "description": "Suggest is followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "consulting",
                "to consult",
                "consult"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I saw him ……………………………. over the wall.",
            "description": "After see, we can use an ing form or an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "jump",
                "jumping",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can smell something …………………………",
            "description": "Smell is followed by an ing form or an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to burn",
                "burning",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She caught him ……………………………… her letters.",
            "description": "Catch is followed by an ing form or an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to read",
                "reading",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She kept the fire ……………………………………",
            "description": "Keep is followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "burning",
                "to burn",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They made him …………………………………..",
            "description": "Make is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to apologize",
                "apologize",
                "apologizing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We found the house ………………………….",
            "description": "Here the meaning is passive – the house was deserted. Hence the past participle is used after find.",
            "answers": [
                "to desert",
                "deserting",
                "deserted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}